Never forget why you are the church.
I want to continue our series upon this
rock.
We are in week three of what will be a seven week series.
We will take a break.
This coming up Sunday.
I'll bring a message outside of the series.
Then we'll catch right back up next Sunday in week four.
But this is all about our core values here at Cedar
Grove Baptist Church.
We have a vision that is Cedar Grove Baptist Church exists
to create a space where people and families can meet Jesus.
Find community and grow in their faith.
We know our mission is our purpose is to love others unconditionally,
learn about God increasingly, live to share Jesus
intentionally and lead others to Christ continually in Lebanon,
Tennessee, and throughout the whole world.
That's why we are here on this earth.
That's how we are going to glorify the Lord with our
actions and our life.
If you look behind me.
The reason why we're doing a series like this is because I can give you a
piece of paper, and we're going to at the end of all this, outlining
all these things, all these points, and all the scriptures.
And it's easy just to get that and say,
cool, kind of like when we give you your stewardship packets, and you
throw them in a car, then you lose them, then all of a sudden you don't have it,
and we're only a month in.
You know what I'm saying?
We have another 11 months to worry about it.
But if you look behind me, if
you're new, you may wonder, like, man, you know, everything looks
pretty cool, but then there's, like, this weird kind of thing on the wall with
these, like, wooden slats and everything, and there's some light and stuff.
What we did is we got together.
I don't know how long ago this was, but we got together and we recorded our church.
saying loudly the word amen.
Now, we know that amen means so be it, right?
Amen is a term of agreement in a body
of believers, okay?
So when you say amen, right?
You need to be agreeing with what is being said.
That's why sometimes when I read scriptures like, for God
so loved the world and everyone's just like, I'm like, amen?
And everyone says, amen, right?
So, but why we did, what we did is we
took that sound wave and we, we,
we printed it off and Mike did as close as he could.
And that is our sound wave of our church in
agreement saying, amen.
Now, why is that important?
It's important because we can try to force this on you all we want.
We can sit here and make up all these visions, all these missions,
all these core values, but guys, we've got to
be in agreement of why we are here at Cedar Grove Baptist Church.
And so if we're going to build this church, as God would want it built, we
must be committed to both the vision and the mission, right?
And listen, I've been here for a long time.
This church has been here for a lot longer, but we're not promised tomorrow.
I'm not promised tomorrow.
But the ministry has to go on.
And the only way the ministry is going to continue to go on no
matter what happens, no matter what this world throws our way,
no matter no matter who's here or who's not here, if the
ministry of Cedar Grove Baptist Church that was started in
the year 1813, no,
no, the incountable number that
people have gotten saved and walking with the Lord right here
on this hill, if that is going to continue, we better
be in agreement about the things that are important.
These are not just ideas or statements to be memorized, although I'd love for you to memorize them.
These are truths to live by.
However, we cannot be committed to the vision and mission unless we do
with the correct foundation.
Jesus speaks on this in Matthew 16, verse 15 through 19.
He says this.
He said to them, but who do you say that I am?
Simon Peter answered?
You are the Christ, the son of the living God.
And Jesus said to him, Blessed are you, Simon Barjona,
because flesh and blood did not reveal this to you, but my Father who is in heaven.
I also say to you that you are Peter and upon this rock,
I will build my church, and the gates of Hades will not overpower it.
I will give you the keys in the kingdom of heaven.
And whatever you bind on earth shall have been bound in heaven, whatever you
loose on earth shall have been loosed in heaven.
Now understand the rock on which we stand as a church is
not anyone person.
It's not any cultural identity.
It is not Peter way back.
It's not a line from Peter.
It's not a particular music preference.
It's not whether we have piers or chairs.
It's n of that.
The rock upon which we stand is Jesus himself.
He is the chief cornerstone of the church.
The profession that he is, Lord.
Listen, if we do not get this right, we have, by
definition, nothing right.
People say, well, they got a lot of it, right?
Well, what do they think about Jesus?
People all the time say, well, I don't really agree with criticizing
other denominations.
Well, hold on.
Who is Jesus to them?
Because if Jesus is not the Christ, the Son of the Living God,
if Jesus is not, do you know why they
crucify Christ?
Not because it was just some because they understood
what he said as him saying that he is God.
Who can forgive sins other than God?
Jesus said, your sins are forgiven.
In other words, we get all this so confused about a deity of Christ,
it was not confusing when he was walking this earth and preaching and teaching.
They knew exactly what this man was saying.
And so why do we get it wrong?
All I'm trying to say is this.
If you've got Jesus wrong, you've got it all wrong.
You are building your house upon the shifting sands of this world.
By the way, the enemy's been trying to peddle that line for a long,
long time.
Amen?
We did not get this right, we have nothing, right?
A big building and many people does not indicate a proper foundation.
The devil was a master manipulator and imitator.
If we're going to grow here, may it be because we have the proper foundation.
This is where our core values come into play.
If we profess Jesus as Lord, this means that we have been made a
new creation, therefore, we have a different set of values
in those who live according to the flesh.
Now, we've gone over 2 of the 7 already the past 2 weeks.
Now I want to just go ahead and make this clear.
We're going to be all over scripture today.
Okay?
If you're thinking, man, I don't I don't like a preacher,
doesn't say turn to a Bible in verse, just wait after these 7 weeks.
We'll go back to our very, very slow study in Romans, okay?
If you don't think I preach verse by verse, just ask anybody who's been here for a while, okay?
We've been in Romans since February of 2024.
And so, but this is more of a topical series,
a little bit out of my comfort zone, but it's something that we have to know.
All right?
So we first looked at this.
I will uphold.
This is our statement of agreement of a core value of family.
I will uphold the sanctity of the family.
Just making family is important is not what we are talking about here, by the way.
There are plenty of people who make their family of such importance that
they become an idol to them.
Did you know that your family can become an idol in your life?
You say, Preacher, I don't agree with that.
My family comes first before anything.
They're an idol then.
Can I tell you something?
Anything, you say, what is an idol, then?
Anything that takes precedence over Christ is
an idol in your life.
It's been that way since the beginning of creation.
And so what I'm trying to say is this.
If you don't love Jesus more than you love your family, if
you don't prioritize Christ more than you prioritize
your family, then you are not even loving your family like you ought to.
We are to uphold the sanctity of family.
That is, our family is sacred.
Our family is holy.
Our family is focused on the things of God together.
We do not allow the world to dictate or control our family,
but rather our family is a priority of ministry
and biblical unity.
Listen, I understand that some people can make this happen, but this whole thing of,
oh, well, we have church at the ballpark.
No, you don't.
How can you have church at the ballpark, then cussed out the ref 30 minutes later.
How can you have church at the ballpark but neglect Christ at every?
We have a little 5 minute prayer, and what's the prayer about?
God, I pray that we hit it hard today.
What are we talking about here?
Now that's just one example.
I know there's many examples, but we've turned this idea
of, well, as long as we're together.
Listen, you know, we can be together in the wrong way.
We all know what that, we've all experienced that
in our lives.
So we must uphold the sanctity of the family.
Our family must be a holy family that
is set apart for the use of God.
But also, I'll live daily with integrity and thought, word, and deed.
So integrity is the second, um, core value.
Remember the definition of integrity in the Old Testament?
The Hebrew word translated integrity means the condition of
being without blemish, completeness, perfection, sincerity,
soundness, uprightness, wholeness.
When we get to the New Testament, it means honest in adherence to
a pattern of good works.
When we think with integrity, we will speak with integrity,
therefore, our actions will also be with integrity.
If any of these three things are off, all three will be affected.
Walking in honesty before God and man means that
you are who you say you are both in private and public.
Listen, you know why I try...
People may say, Preach, you're kind of rough around the edges.
You know why?
Because I'm not trying to put on a facade here.
I want to be this...
When we talk, I want to be the same kind of person that I am in the pulpit that I
am outside the pulpit.
I'm about to lose my voice, y'all.
And I got to worship that tonight.
Oh, man, y'all pray for me.
But listen, seriously, I don't want to be sitting here all prim and proper
and this and that and make listen,
I live life just like you do.
I live in the world just like you do.
I struggle just like you do.
I get tempted and tried just like you do.
I'm trying to follow Christ just like you.
I'm trying to raise a family for the Lord just like you are.
The beauty of the beauty of that is, hey, if we do it together with integrity, guess what?
It becomes a lot easier to go through those hard times.
So we got to walk in integrity.
Our next core value is relationships, relationships.
We're going to pray.
Father, we thank you, Lord, for this day.
We thank you for your word.
God, as we break down some of these scriptures, God, I pray, Lord, that those that have
ears to hear, may they hear?
And God will just thank you and we love you.
In Jesus' name, pray.
Amen.
The statement of agreement for this core value of relationships is,
I will build and grow each of the four relationships
represented in the purpose statement of my church.
Now, these should all sound very familiar this morning, because we read
it to you two or three times already.
Each one of our mission statement parts speak on our relationships
in certain capacities.
The first being, I will build and grow each of the four
relationships representing the purpose statement of my church by seeking
to love others unconditionally.
Now, this speaks of our relationship with others, obviously.
And before I go any further, I want to emphasize an important part of the series again.
We are attempting to teach you what it looks like to value the right things in your life.
This does not just apply to you, but also to me as well.
I talked about that just a minute ago.
I believe the church has done a great job of coming up with
strong vision and mission statements.
Many churches have core values that are right on and makes sense,
man, you amen, each of them.
The church does a great job of branding and marketing what they
would like to be and be about.
So where is the disconnect then?
If we got all these nice statements and all these nice things and
all this, all this, I mean, we got an amazing website, an amazing app.
We got immediate player.
We got an online present social media wise.
What becomes a disconnect so often?
Our job as members of this church is not simply to repeat
words and models, if all we do is just repeat them
and memorize a few statements just to show that we are in, we
are missing the whole point, we have to do what we know is right.
As a matter of fact, the Bible says in James, that if you don't
do what you know is right, it is sin unto you.
So people say this, I'm going to trap you here for a second.
And I don't mean to trap you in scripture, but sometimes I get trapped in scripture, so I guess you can too.
Amen?
Truth sometimes just puts me in like, uh-oh, I got I have a decision to make here.
Do you agree that church is good?
That hurt my feelings.
Because like four, you said, yeah, sure.
Do you agree that church is good?
Okay, Miss Geraldine, she can't be with us.
Um, she's at the, uh, assisted living, but
she long time member.
I pretty sure she's been a member here.
Possibly she might be in the picture with the 1st building,
and I'm just kidding.
Um, But she is.
Do what?
Yeah, you tell her.
That's her granddaughter.
I forgot she was here.
Yeah, you tell her, Katie.
Anyway, um, but, but no,
she, uh, every man, she would, she'd sit in the back row, of course.
And every single time church was over.
She would look at me, and she'd come up, and she'd have a little, you know, cane
and stuff, and she'd look up, and she said, Good church
preacher, and I'd be like, Good church.
And then I'd hear her husband, Come on, woman, because he'd want to leave church.
But anyway, listen, it's, uh, do you agree that church is good?
Yes, amen.
Okay.
Well, when people say, do I really have to go to
church to be saved?
That's kind of a question, really, in my opinion,
asked out of an improper heart posture.
Because the answer is, no, you don't have to go to church to be saved.
That's only through Jesus.
But if you are saved, you're going to want to go to church.
It's kind of like something, if you're married,
you don't have to be married.
You don't have to go home to be married.
You can party all you want all weekend.
You can still be married on Monday.
You better go home.
You understand what I'm saying?
Listen, it's a relationship.
Right?
Our salvation is a relationship with Christ.
We are the bride of Christ, the churches.
And so it's not necessarily, well, if, if, if, do I have to be safe to go to church?
No, no, no.
We know that church is good.
As a matter of fact, those that come to church and get plugged in and
are part of something and have that purpose and see the vision
and live the mission and understand the core
values and value the same things.
Let me just tell you something.
Just test it.
Your life is gonna be better.
You say, well, preacher said, I'm telling you right now, I've seen
people that have it, and I've seen people that do.
Your life will be better.
You walk with Christ will be closer.
You'll be able to walk through the tough times and the good times with
others that understand.
And so, yes, we got to understand, we want to grow.
We want to grow in this.
We wanna seek to love others unconditionally.
We got to do what we're saying we're about.
But again, what does it mean to love others unconditionally?
Well, it means to love them in the condition they are in.
Jesus spoke on this in John 15, verse 12 through 13.
This is my commandment that you love one another.
Just as I loved you as I have loved you.
Greater love has no one than this than that
one laid down his life for his friends.
Now, what does this have to do with someone's condition?
Well, what was our condition when Jesus laid down his life for us?
Lost.
Sinful, wicked, vile.
Romans 5, 8, but God demonstrates his own love towards us in
that while we were yet sinners, Christ died for us.
Listen, that word that word sinner literally means
it's pretty simple, sinful.
It denotes a sinful behavior.
I feel like sometimes that we have been, some of us have been
saved for so long that we forget just how sinful we were before Christ.
We forget just how just how unlovable that we
really were, but yet God still loved us
and God still saved us.
This word sinvoy can be used derogatorily describe people,
to describe individuals who are guilty of specific sins, or to
describe humanity's natural relationship to God before Christ.
We are in a sinful, lost, hopeless state.
This term senators not just describe who we are, but also what we
do when you came to Christ, you did not do so cleaned up already.
There's a misunderstanding of church here today.
that you've got to somehow, well, I got some things I got to figure out in
my life before I come to Christ.
Come to Christ, he figures them out.
You understand what I'm saying?
We're missing.
We missing something here.
Well, I don't go to church.
I just got to clean myself up.
Listen, that's like that's like cleaning yourself up before you go get a shower.
If I ever see you scrubbing your armpits before you get in a shower, you dirty for real, right?
And no one does that.
That doesn't make any sense.
But what I'm trying to say is, listen, it's not that we clean ourselves up.
That's what the world's trying to do.
The world's trying to tell you.
You just do enough good and God will accept it.
You just do one good day to day and you'll be fine.
Hopefully the scales will turn in your favor.
Let me just tell you something.
I wouldn't bet my life on that.
My eternity on that.
You know why?
The Bible says that's not how it works.
There's none good.
No, not one.
There's none righteous.
That includes you.
That includes me.
So when we sit here and we look at this, we gotta understand.
God loved us before we were even lovable.
In a sinful state.
We invite people to church, we just tell them, come as you are.
talking about loving unconditionally.
We say, yeah, just come on as you are.
There's no dress code.
There's no this, there's no that.
Until they do.
And all of a sudden, when they do, we get all awkward and uncomfortable,
and they don't really look like us, so they
don't really act like us, so they don't really, they don't know the system like we know.
What's going on here?
Listen, it's easier said and done to love unconditionally.
But let's not forget how Jesus found us in Ephesians 2, it says this,
and you are dead in your trespasses and sins.
In which you formerly walked according to the course of this world, according
to the prince, the power of the spirit that is now working in
the sons of disobedience.
Among them, we two all formerly lived in the
lust of our flesh, indulging in the desires of the flesh,
and of the mind, and we're by nature children of wrath,
even as the rest.
Let me just tell you something.
That's bleak right there.
But that's who you were.
That's who I was.
But verse four, 2 of the most beautiful words in all scripture, but God.
But God, being rich in mercy because of his great love, which
he loved us, even when we were dead in
our transgressions, made us alive together with Christ,
by grace, you have been saved.
God loved us even before he saved us.
Isn't God awesome?
You must love people no matter the condition they are in.
This does not mean that we tolerate or support their sins.
Sometimes the best way to love someone is love them from afar.
Guys, remember, we got to abhor that which is evil.
That word abhor means to distance ourselves.
I'm not trying to, listen, I'm not no counseling guru.
I'm not trying to say I got all the answers, but I feel like so often, we
use the term loving unconditionally, but in
reality, we're enabling someone to continue to walk after the lust of flesh.
Well, I just love them.
I can't tell no, you better tell them.
I'd rather tell them they're doing wrong than them dying going to hell.
Jesus never tolerated someone's sin.
Yet Jesus loved the people he encountered every single time.
Unconditional love is not afraid of saying the rough truth with
a tough truth in a loving way.
Why?
Because our love is not predicated on someone's response to our love.
Let me say that again for you, 'cause this is something that spoke to me.
Our love is not predicated or
dependent on someone's response to our love.
Listen, I've called people out for their sin.
I been caught out for doing wrong.
I understand for my sin.
I get it.
It don't feel good.
When you get rebuked, that's a word we don't like.
But I've called people out for their sin, and they've left.
Listen, that hurts.
That hurts me, because I know that, like, oh, no, no, no, no.
Listen, I'm not doing this out of hate.
I'm not doing this out of judgment.
I'm doing this out of love, legit.
I need you to understand that if you continue going down this path, it's not gonna be good.
Remember, God, remember his goodness.
But can I tell you something?
I can't change the message of the gospel just so they come back to church.
I can't change the truth of God's word, just to retain a friend.
One of the greatest descriptions of unconditional love is found in 1 Corinthians
13, 4 through 7, love is patient.
Love is kind and is not jealous.
Love is not bragging is not arrogant, does not act unbecomingly.
It does not seek its own, it's not provoked, it's not taken account
of wrong suffered, does not rejoice in unrighteousness, but
rejoices with the truth, bears all things, believes all things,
hopes all things, endures all things.
That's unconditional love.
You know why it's hard to love unconditionally?
Because it takes such an intentionality.
It takes such spiritually fixed skin.
It's so often, it's easier just to just to love when it's easy.
If you've been married for any amount of time, listen, people say all the time, Oh,
I've loved my wife the
same every day of my life, shut your face.
You a liar.
You a sinning liar.
Okay?
Oh, Taylor just got, you just got rebuked, son.
Bri said, No, you did, yeah.
Tell you what, oh, yes, ma'am.
Put the hat back on.
Oh, y'all gotta sit in front every single Sunday, all right?
But no, think about it for a second.
Listen, hey, again.
Marriage gets tough.
I know, listen, whether you're married or not, I just need you to know, marriage gets tough.
It's two people coming together as one, right?
If you know me, and you know Heather, you know that we're two very different people.
I mean, our personalities are different.
I mean there's a lot of differences here.
In those days that it's like, man, I don't really like how she's treating me.
I don't like this.
I don't like that.
Listen, it's not about it's not about the lovey dovey feelings.
It's about the commitment that I made on a day we got married.
Hey, I'm going to choose to love you every single day,
no matter the condition you're in.
That's what it's about right there.
Guess what?
That's the same thing we have for each other.
You gotta choose to love each other.
You just have to.
How easy do we give up on somebody?
God help us love others like Jesus loves us.
So we're gonna move on now.
I will build and grow each of our, each of the four relationships represented
in the purpose statement of my church, also by growing in
our faith through learning about God increasingly.
Now, this speaks of our relationship with the Lord and his word.
This is one blind spot in too many churches.
We come to church and expect to get fed and to get fed and to get fed.
We pay a preacher to teach us the Bible.
We expect volunteers from the church to teach us and our children about God.
We have offloaded a responsibility
God gave us individually to somebody else.
And if we see something or hear something that we do not like, we immediately
get defensive in a self righteous way.
I got to tell you something this morning with all the love of my heart.
If we are not studying for ourselves at home, or
teaching our kids ourselves at home, I
really do not have time for your opinion or complaint about how we do things here.
Again, I know that came off really rough.
But all I'm trying to say is this.
If this is all you have, and that's the reason why you're thinking, it has to be perfect.
It has to be this, it has to be that.
There's a problem here.
We're just coming alongside you.
Listen, I get it.
We do everything we can here is Cedar Grove to teach the word.
It is of the utmost priority for every leader for every ministry.
Teach the word.
Give a lesson.
Make sure they know the gospel, right?
But we cannot outdo the time you have away from here.
We are to be growing in the faith personally through learning increasingly.
This means that we are learning every day.
And listen, if you don't think that the temptation that I
have, I teach so much, I study to
teach so much.
I feel like every time I open the Bible.
I'm trying to preach something to somebody, right?
I'm teaching Upper Academy.
I do some SCA still every now.
I see you at the poll.
You know, we do Wednesday night.
We do Sunday morning.
I'm getting some preaching around.
All these things.
It's preaching, teaching, preaching, teaching.
And like, just be honest, when I get home, I am done.
I'm like, I don't want to, I want to lay on
this couch and stare at this TV and just go numb.
You know what I'm saying?
Like, that's what I want to do.
You say, preacher.
Get over yourself.
Amen?
I'm just letting you know how it is.
It's hard.
And sometimes, listen, my girls come home and they tell me
something about God's word, I'm like, where'd you learn that from?
I say, Miss Carolyn,
Miss Janice, Miss Millie, Miss Heather.
Miss whoever it is, if I missed your name, I love you, and I'm sorry.
But all I'm trying to say is, listen, hey, that's amazing,
and that's great, and I love it.
But every single time it convicts me.
What have you learned from me?
I'm your father.
I'm the one that's responsible for your spiritual well being.
Guys, we got to understand it, we got to learn increasingly.
If all you're getting is here,
You're not getting enough.
King David wrote of this in Psalm 24, 4 through 5.
Make me know your ways, O Lord.
Teach me your past, lead me in your truth, and teach me, for you are the God of
my salvation, for you, I wait all the day.
You show me a carnal and worldly church.
I'll show you a congregation that is not increasingly learning about God.
You cannot increasingly learn about God and stay the same.
Listen, we cannot live only after what we learned as a kid.
Sometimes I feel like people just repeat the same thing over and over
again because that's what they learned 1st about God and that's
what they've hung on their entire life.
And listen, that is great, but we've gotta go deeper.
Don't just believe something because someone you liked or followed
told you that's what to believe.
Go to God's word, learn from him.
You may be surprised.
A thriving church, the church where the people has a hunger for God's word.
When is the last time you ask God to lead you in his truth to teach you in his ways?
So we move on here.
We're going to go very quickly.
You want me to say amen?
I will build and grow each of the 4 relationships represented in the purpose
statement of my church by building up the church through
living to share Jesus intentionally.
This one and the next one speaks of our relationship with the mission.
March 16, 14 through 15, after what he appeared to the 11
themselves as they were reclining at the table, and he
reproached them for their unbelief and hardness of heart because they
had not believed those who had seen him after he had risen.
And he said to them, go into all the world and preach
the gospel to all creation.
Can I tell you something?
Not everyone is a pastor.
But everyone's a preacher.
Does that language make you uncomfortable?
I know in ESBC.
Oh, oh, oh, what are you saying?
Listen, not everyone's a pastor.
But everyone's a proclaimer of truth.
That word preach literally means to preach or proclaim,
refers to publicly preaching or proclaiming a message.
This is what it is to share the good news of Jesus, the gospel,
the truth that Jesus lived, died for our sins, and rose again the 3rd day.
Me, you, we, everyone who is saved is to
proclaim this, to share the good news of Christ.
He is alive.
It breaks my heart when I hear someone say things like this.
Well, I just don't know what to say.
Well, I can't go soul winning because God
just created me too shy.
Well, hold on.
God doesn't contradict himself.
God knew you were shy when he gave this command.
It doesn't listen, your Bible doesn't have an asterisk unless you're shy.
That's ridiculous, but yet we put that after again there.
I'll let someone else do that.
I'll let the professional Christians do that.
I'll let the staff do that.
I'll let those that have that big person that, listen, hey, you know what?
Sometimes big personalities can't reach certain people, but you can.
Look, I get around certain people.
They're like, dude, I don't want nothing you have.
I'm just telling you right now, you're crazy.
But you get around them, they'll listen.
They'll hear the gospel.
That might be why God created us so differently.
That's some good, that's some good preaching right there.
You're too shy about the fact that Jesus saved you?
God forbid.
All you have to share is what Jesus did for you.
And if it's anything other than what we see clearly in scriptures, if
your testimony is anything but the fact that you confess
Jesus, Lord, and believe in your heart that God raised from the dead, listen, you called upon the name of the Lord.
If it's anything different than that, you need to be led to Christ.
I've heard so many people.
And older people say, what sister,
brother, give me your testimony.
Oh, well, I've been in church my whole life.
Nine months before I was born.
I was in church.
That's cool.
Give your testimony.
It has to include Jesus.
You understand what I'm saying?
And so listen, this brings us to our final part of the day.
I will build and grow each of the four relationships represented
in the purpose statement of my church by expanding the kingdom of
God through leading others to Christ continually.
This is what it's all about.
The Great Commission in Matthew 28, starting in verse 18,
and Jesus came up and spoke to them, saying, all authority has been given to me in heaven
and on earth.
Go, therefore, and make disciples of all the nations, baptizing
them in the name of the Father and the Son, and the Holy Spirit, teaching them
to observe all that I commanded you.
And lo, I am with you always, even to the end of the age.
I hear all time.
Well, preacher, I'm just not one to care about numbers.
I feel like you talk about numbers too much.
You don't feel that way about your business.
You don't feel that way about your bank accounts.
All of a sudden, every other aspect of our life,
numbers matters.
We get into God's house, all of a sudden numbers don't matter anymore.
Church, listen to me.
The more people come to know Christ, the
more people come to know Christ.
You understand what I'm saying?
I'm gonna repeat that for the people that are six rows back.
The more people come to know Christ, the more people will come to know Christ.
That's the whole point of all of this.
Listen, dead churches do not care about numbers because they don't have any.
They are filled with believers who have either grown cold in their walk,
stagnant in their faith, apathetic towards the things of God.
We talk about dead churches.
That's an oxy moron.
How can you be a dead church serving a risen savior?
By the way, the dead church over there, they got the same Holy Spirit
and dwell within that we have here.
What going on?
Now, that doesn't mean that just because a church is small, it's out of God's will.
Listen, we got a small church right here.
But that church better be going after the lost and community.
Better be after the right things.
When I 1st got here, there were some people that was saying, I just kind of want
my, I just want my little,
little church on the hill.
I said, why?
There's nothing going on.
They said, I just like it how it is.
Well, it's gonna change.
Why?
Because more people are gonna come.
And when more people come, things change.
People lose power.
I'm gonna get into a whole 'nother message.
That's for business meeting time, you know what I'm saying?
But, no, seriously, think about it for a second.
We want what we want.
I literally had someone tell me one time that we, you know, we were packed out to the,
talking about packed out.
He said, Preacher, listen, you know what?
At some point, we're going to just make a decision.
We can't fit no more people.
We got enough people.
I almost punched him around his throat.
What are you talking about?
God says, we can't we can't think that way.
The more people that come know Christ, the more people will come to know Christ.
That's what it's all about.
So how do we do this?
By loving others unconditionally.
Learning about God increasingly, living the share Jesus intentionally,
leading others to Christ continually in Lebanon, Tennessee, and throughout the whole world.
Maybe we grow in these relationships.
I want to leave you at this challenge this morning, the same challenge that Paul
gave the believers in Rome.
We know in Romans 10, 13, one of the greatest scriptures written, Whosover
shall call, in the name of Lord, will be saved.
Amen.
I love it.
I love that.
We complicate salvation so much that we
put all these parameters and all these things that we have to do.
Listen, that's work based.
Faith-based is God save me.
I can do nothing.
Verse 14, though, in Romans 10, how then were they calling him
in whom they have not believed?
How will they believe in him and whom they have not heard?
How are they here without a preacher?
That word preacher?
Proclaimer of truth.
How will they preach unless they are sent?
We just talked about it.
You're sent, just as it is written, how beautiful are the
feet of those who bring good news of good things?
When's the last time you brought the good news?
That's a convicting question, church.
When's the last time I'm asking the same question myself this morning?
When is the last time, outside of this setting, I could easily say, Well,
I give the good news every Sunday.
No, no, no.
Again, remember, I live in the same world you live in.
When is the last time?
that you truly just stopped.
and shared the good news.
Oh, well, they'll probably say no.
That doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter.
Oh, well, they'll probably get mad.
Listen, how other people receive the
good news is not up to us.
We can let God handle that.
What's up to us?
Are we gonna do what God has commanded or not?
I pray we choose to do.
But Hezban Asclo is over his place.